<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>IMACS - Institute for Malaria and Climate Solutions Blog</title>
        <link>https://Forecasting-Healthy-Futures.github.io/homepage/homepage/blog</link>
        <description>IMACS - Institute for Malaria and Climate Solutions Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Welcome]]></title>
            <link>https://Forecasting-Healthy-Futures.github.io/homepage/homepage/blog/welcome</link>
            <guid>welcome</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Changing the world is possible. We need affordable technologies.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_mojV" id="changing-the-world-is-possible-we-need-affordable-technologies">Changing the world is possible. We need affordable technologies.<a class="hash-link" href="#changing-the-world-is-possible-we-need-affordable-technologies" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>With every second of a health provider's time wasted in paperwork, humanity loses one of its very own. Digital health has not only brought the care providers and beneficiaries closer than ever before, but it has also provided the opportunity to free off health providers' time and empower them with access to information about what works.</p><p>The real application of digital health began after the 1980s when several American associations started focusing on improving health communications and informatics using digital health. With the growth of data and its associated science, digital health took a new leap post-2000. The past five years witnessed an unprecedented boom in the digital health industry as artificial intelligence and automation eased predictions and workflows in many facets of health.</p><p>Today digital health is ubiquitous yet inequitably distributed, with the marginalized communities having little access to the most modern digital health solutions. Moreover, the inequalities and injustice in healthcare delivery, skewed access to technologies such as smartphones, and the disproportionate impact of climate change, socio-economic issues, and emerging infections have furthered the scope of benefitting the most marginalized.  </p><p>At this outset, it is crucial to design solutions that are affordable and accessible to communities living in poverty. But, more importantly, it is quintessential to define their pricing and delivery models that enable sustainable businesses despite focusing on equitable community benefit.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>digital health</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Digital Health with AI and ML]]></title>
            <link>https://Forecasting-Healthy-Futures.github.io/homepage/homepage/blog/Digital Health with AI and ML</link>
            <guid>Digital Health with AI and ML</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Digital health, which includes the use of electronic health records, telemedicine, and wearable devices, has revolutionized the healthcare industry. However, the adoption of these technologies has also created a massive amount of data that needs to be processed and analyzed. This is where AI, ML, and cloud computing come in. By leveraging these technologies, we can transform digital health and make it more effective, efficient, and accessible.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Transforming digital health using AI ML and Cloud computing</h1><p>Digital health, which includes the use of electronic health records, telemedicine, and wearable devices, has revolutionized the healthcare industry. However, the adoption of these technologies has also created a massive amount of data that needs to be processed and analyzed. This is where AI, ML, and cloud computing come in. By leveraging these technologies, we can transform digital health and make it more effective, efficient, and accessible.</p><p>AI and ML have the ability to process and analyze large amounts of data quickly and accurately. They can help identify patterns and trends in patient data, such as predicting which patients are at risk of developing certain conditions or identifying which treatments are most effective. This can help healthcare providers make more informed decisions and provide more personalized care.</p><p>Cloud computing, on the other hand, provides a scalable and secure infrastructure for storing and processing this data. It allows healthcare providers to access patient data from anywhere and at any time, while also ensuring that the data is protected and compliant with regulations.</p><p>One area where AI, ML, and cloud computing are making a significant impact is in the field of precision medicine. Precision medicine involves tailoring treatments to individual patients based on their genetic makeup, lifestyle, and other factors. By analyzing patient data using AI and ML algorithms, healthcare providers can identify patterns and relationships that can help guide treatment decisions.</p><p>Another area where these technologies are being used is in remote patient monitoring. With the rise of telemedicine, patients can now receive care from the comfort of their own homes. Wearable devices and other connected devices can be used to collect patient data, which can be processed and analyzed in the cloud. Healthcare providers can then monitor patients in real-time and provide more personalized care.</p><p>AI, ML, and cloud computing are also being used to improve the efficiency of healthcare operations. For example, they can be used to optimize scheduling, reduce wait times, and improve patient flow. This can help healthcare providers to see more patients and provide more effective care.</p><p>In conclusion, the transformation of digital health using AI, ML, and cloud computing is revolutionizing the healthcare industry. These technologies are making it possible to process and analyze large amounts of data quickly and accurately, while also providing a secure and scalable infrastructure for storing and accessing this data. As a result, we can provide more personalized and efficient care to patients, while also reducing costs and improving outcomes.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>digital health AI ML</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>